

Yechiel Kalmenson

Full-Stack Web Developer

(347) 500-0422 | hire@yechiel.me | Github: achasveachas | www.yechiel.me

Professional Highlights

- Experience working, teaching, and learning remotely
- Specializes in teaching and learning in non-traditional environments
- Familiar with HTML/CSS, Ruby, Rails, Javascript/jQuery, ReactJS
- Customer-Service people oriented
- > Fluent in English, Hebrew, and Yiddish

See more of my projects on my GitHub profile: https://github.com/achasveachas

Select Projects

App Tracker

An online tool for job seekers to track their job applications. It's a ReactJS/Redux app talking to a Rails RESTful API with a PostgreSQL Database on the back end.

- Rails REST API built using a TDD pattern with RSpec
- Uses React-Router for RESTful routing
- Utilizes JWT Tokens for Client-Side authentication

Source Code: https://github.com/achasveachas/app-tracker-react

Live Version: https://app-tracker-react.herokuapp.com

Blog Post: https://blog.yechiel.me/reactjs-app-with-rails-api-4ffb12ba6608

Corneal

A Ruby gem that generates the basic structure for Sinatra apps, including Model and Scaffold generators built after the Rails Model and Scaffold generators.

- Collaborated with fellow students on an open-source project
- Contributed a Scaffold Generator that uses Thor to generate the MVC structure of a resource

Source Code: https://github.com/thebrianemory/corneal

Live Version: https://rubygems.org/gems/corneal

Blog Post: https://blog.yechiel.me/of-scaffolds-and-gems-140bdbe2e005#.bn1covkp7

Freddit

A basic Reddit clone featuring threads with nested comments.

- Built using Rails for the backend of the project
- Front-end uses jQuery to render forms, and post content to the DOM
- Included earlier Sinatra version of the app

Source Code: Rails/jQuery: https://github.com/achasveachas/freddit-jq

Sinatra: https://github.com/achasveachas/freddit

Live Version: Rails/jQuery: https://freddit-jq.herokuapp.com/

Blog Post: Rails/jQuery: https://blog.yechiel.me/challenges-revisited-33ae6ab648ae#.janyd1e5j

Sinatra: https://blog.yechiel.me/i-challenge-you-sinatra-c6f875e29db7#.9x4318940

FlyLog

An online pilot logbook, where pilots can log their flight hours.

- Built using Rails with a PostgreSQL database
- Uses OmniAuth for OAuth authentication with GitHub

Source Code: https://github.com/achasveachas/FlyLog

Live Version: https://flylogger.herokuapp.com/

Blog Post: https://blog.yechiel.me/fly-off-the-rails-78f3e4e82e72#.uwmnx5js7

Experience

FIDELITY PAYMENT SERVICES - Brooklyn, NY

2015 – Present

Integration - Tech Support

Provides integration support to our merchants for physical POS systems as well as online payment gateways.

<u>Responsibilities include</u>: providing support via phone and email as well as remote sessions, deploying new accounts, researching and providing options for integrating merchants' existing payment solutions with our software, researching and compiling reports to management on the performance of the tech-support team.

Jewish Online School - Remote

2011 - 2015

Teacher - 3rd Grade

Taught Jewish Studies in an online setting for children in remote communities all over the world.

<u>Responsibilities included</u>: preparing lessons (making sure they are engaging enough for 3rd graders a mouse-click away from YouTube), tracking students' progress, communicating with parents and faculty via email and phone.

CHABAD OUTREACH - International

2001 - Present

Outreach Volunteer

Volunteered in various locations around the world.

<u>Responsibilities included</u>: organizing holiday events including the largest Passover Seder in the world, teaching both in one-on-one and larger class settings, helping build and translate websites for various Chabad Centers.

Education

FLATIRON SCHOOL - New-York, NY

2017

Full Stack Web Development

United Lubavitch Yeshivah – Brooklyn, NY

2010

Rabbinic Ordination